radiopaedia.org 2015-06-27

# Privacy Policy | Radiopaedia.org

#### Our commitment to privacy

Your privacy, and that of your patients is very important to Radiopaedia.org. To better protect your privacy and that of your patients, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

#### The information we collect about you

Required information for registration consists of:

  * Username and password
  * Surname
  * First name
  * Position (professional)
  * Country
  * email address

Additional information including, but not limited to, city, institution and title can also be entered during registration and on your  user profile page. 

As much of the site is contributed by users, it may be that further personal information is posted by individual users. 

#### The way we use information

##### Email address

The email address you provide us is very important to our communication with you. Your email address is used in four distinct ways.

First, your email address will be used to allow users to contact you via ‘contact user’ link in your profile. When such contact is initiated, your email address remains hidden. You can opt-out of being contacted by other users in your profile settings. 

Second, the editorial board may contact you in regards to your contributions. In doing so, an email will be sent to the address you provided. You cannot opt-out of this type of communication.

Third, to facilitate communication with you in a professional way, including managing unsubscribe requests and newsletter publishing, your email address will be upload to a trusted third party service provider which handles these kind of services. For newsletters or other opt-in communications, you can always opt out of receiving these emails.

Finally, very rarely, Radiopaedia may need to send important announcements to you, such as changes to this privacy policy or alterations to the site’s terms of use. You cannot opt out of this kind of email. 

##### Other information

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers / sponsors. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of registrars or consultants are registered members, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

#### Anonymity of cases / images

All cases submitted should be de-identified, in such a way as to leave no way of identifying an individual patient. Information which should **NOT** appear on any of the cases includes (based on [HIPAA](http://www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/understanding/summary/) guidelines), but is not limited to:

  * name
  * initials
  * date of birth
  * address, including full or partial postal code
  * telephone or fax numbers or contact information
  * e-mail addresses
  * unique identifying numbers (e.g. UR, MRN, HID etc..)
  * vehicle identifiers
  * medical device identifiers (e.g serial numbers)
  * web or internet protocol addresses containing any link to the patient
  * biometric data
  * facial photograph or comparable image
  * names of relatives
  * date of study

Additionally if a case is for one reason or another unique in such a way that could lead to identification of an individual from the images alone then it should also not be uploaded. This means that a case which is has, for example, been featured in the media is usually inappropriate for upload. 

Similarly the textual information accompanying the text should also be devoid of identifying information, and devoid of other unnecessary information which could aid in the identification of a patient. 

Note: Our privacy policy does not override the individual policies of institutions and users should ensure that they are using images within their local guidelines. 

We take this **very seriously** , and failure to abide by these rules a breach of our privacy policy and terms of use. If you upload a case with patient information, your case will be immediately deleted and if you repeatedly upload cases with patient details your account will be suspended. 

If you find such a case please contact us at [privacy@radiopaedia.org](mailto:privacy@radiopaedia.org).

#### Our commitment to data security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

#### How you can access or correct your information

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by accessing your user profile page. 

#### How to contact us in regards to privacy concerns

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an email at [privacy@radiopaedia.org](mailto:privacy@radiopaedia.org).
